<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="ans">
        <item> There are a plethora of roles out there for data analysts, across a range of industries.
            Your response to this question will tell the interviewer about your thought process in
            choosing this role. In your response, discuss why you were drawn to data analysis in the
            first place, the key skills you’ll bring to the role, and why you’re interested in this
            role in particular. And remember: Enthusiasm goes a long way!
“A data analyst’s job is to take data and use it to help companies make better business decisions.
            I want to make a tangible impact in my job, so that aspect really appeals to me.
            Additionally, I’ve loved numbers since I was a little kid, and I’m good at collecting
            data and doing market research, so this field seemed like a natural fit. This role lets
            me use my skills in a collaborative environment, where I can learn from some of the best
            minds in the industry.”
 </item>
        <item> There are many types of data analyst roles, including operations analysts, marketing
            analysts, financial analysts, and business analysts. Your answer should be based on your
            individual preferences. Be specific in your response to show the interviewer that you’ve
            done your research.

“I would prefer to work as a marketing analyst because it’s most in line with my skills and interests.
            I love studying consumer behavior and having a real impact on a company’s success.
            In addition, I’ve seen that companies that hire for this role work in growing industries
            and can therefore provide good career growth and exciting opportunities.”
</item>
        <item>This question tells the interviewer whether you have the necessary hard skills—and it
            can provide insight into areas in which you might need further training. In your answer,
            include any tools emphasized in the job description, as well as your individual experience
            with those tools. Be sure to use familiar terminology. Here’s a sample answer:

“I’ve used a variety of tools over the past few years. At my current employer, I use Weka for
            data management and data mining tasks. I’ve been using Excel since I first started
            doing data analysis, and I’m also fairly well versed in Python, Tableau, and SQL.”
        </item>
        <item> With a question like this, the interviewer gains insight into how you approach
            and solve problems and gets a better idea of the type of work you have already done.
            To ensure you focus on the details and subsequent result, use the STAR method for
            this behavioral interview question. Avoid blaming others in your response; instead,
            focus on how you overcame the challenges to yield a successful result.
“My most difficult project was a pricing optimization problem. I was given five products, each
            of which had different pros and cons. They varied in quality and customer reviews,
            and my company wanted to identify the highest prices we could charge without
            significantly reducing demand for the products. It was really tough because I was
            unfamiliar with optimization algorithms, but I utilized an algorithm that identified
            the relative price of each product, and I scaled them to absolute prices using
            historical data. Then, I tracked sales after setting the prices to identify how they
            affected demand, and I iterated on the prices to ensure optimization. Ultimately,
            the project led to our increasing sales revenue by 20 percent.”
 </item>
        <item> Interviewers ask this type of question to get a better picture of your thought
            process without the help of computers and data sets. In your answer, clearly and
            concisely walk the interviewer through your process, touching on how you would
            identify the variables/data segments. The interviewer is looking for your ability
            to communicate your thought process, as well as your overall creativity. This example
            response touches on all these points:
“First, I would gather data on how many people live in France. Then, I’d identify what
            percentage of
those people purchase cheese and the average amount of cheese each buyer purchases. Since I’mlooking
for buying patterns in a specific month, I’d find out if there’s a seasonality to buying
cheese. If May was a more popular month for purchasing cheese, I would scale my
calculations accordingly.”
</item>
        <item>Communication is key in any position. As a data analyst, you will be expected to
successfully present your findings and translate your numerical findings into accessible
concepts and themes. Assure the interviewer of your ability to communicate with an answer
like this:
“My greatest communication strength would have to be my ability to relay information. I’m good at
speaking in a simple, effective manner, so that even people who aren’t familiar with the
terms can grasp the overall concepts. I think communication is extremely valuable in a
 role like this, especially when it comes to presenting my findings. Data doesn’t do any
good if no one understands what it means.”
</item>
        <item>In asking this question, the interviewer wants to ensure that you won’t crack under
pressure. The best way to answer this question is to use the STAR method to give a
specific example of how you handled stress in a previous job, internship, or class.
That way, the interviewer can get a clear picture of how well you work in demanding
situations. Avoid mentioning a time when you put yourself in a needlessly stressful
situation. Rather, describe a time when you were given a difficult task or multiple
 assignments and rose to the occasion:
“I actually work better under pressure; I’ve found that I enjoy working in a challenging environment.
I get really energized by short turnarounds and multiple projects because I have to
prioritize and produce. Then, I actually do some of my best work. For example, last year,
I had three major essays due in the same week, which was a lot of pressure. However,
I broke each day into blocks of time and created a schedule that detailed how I would
break down each essay into individual components with clear deadlines. In the end, I
completed all three essays ahead of time—and avoided additional stress.”
</item>
        <item>This is similar to the classic question, “Where do you see yourself in five years?”
The interviewer wants to know that you’re in this for the long run and that you’re a good
fit. Knowing what the company wants and values will help you speak to your ability
to solve their unique problems and grow with them. Do not discuss your personal goals
outside of work, such as having a family or traveling around the world.
Instead, do your research ahead of time, using their website, recent news articles,
and LinkedIn. Then, highlight how your goals fit with their culture and future plans.
“My long-term goals involve growing with a company and continuing to learn, taking on additional
responsibilities, and contributing as much value as I can. As a data analyst,
I look forward to taking on increasingly complex problems. I love that your company
is mission-driven, as working in a role where I can have a concrete positive impact
is important to me.”
</item>
          <item>In asking this question, the interviewer is really asking, “What makes you the best
fit for this position?” Your answer should be a concise sales pitch that explains
 what you have to offer the employer. Keep it short and confident, highlighting what
differentiates you from all the other data analysts out there.
“I’ve worked across a variety of industries and will bring that knowledge to your company to
 deliver innovative solutions. I also have a track of success, both academically and
professionally, so you know that I can get results. And while many data analysts prefer
to be behind a computer, I love interfacing with others and pride myself on my strong
communication skills—so I can code, do presentations, and talk to clients.
 </item>
        <item>At the close of the interview, most interviewers ask whether you have any questions
about the job or company. As a data analyst, your job is to ask the hard questions,
find the gaps, and determine the solutions, so you should have some strong questions
at the ready. Ask questions about the role, the company, or the team:
“How does the [analytics] team communicate their findings to the rest of the company?”
“What are some examples of recent work that the team has done?”
“What will the onboarding and training process look like?” </item>

    </string-array>
</resources>